--------ED------------
Long time no see, Mii.
久しぶりだな　美偉
Sempai...
先輩
You're alive!
生きてたんですね
It seems so.
みたいだな
Why?
なんで　なんで　何の連絡もくれなかったんです
Why didn't you contact me?!
I thought you just...
あたし　てっきり
Don't worry.
安心しろ
I'll disappear again in no time.
すぐに消えるさ
Sempai!
先輩
Sempai...
響き合う願いが今覚醒めてく
脑海中回响着的愿望现已苏醒
譲れない未来のために
为了绝不可相让的未来
巡り逢う運命を超えたその先に
只因在超越命运的前方
この想い輝くから
这份思念正闪耀着光芒
ここじゃない未来に
在那并非归属的未来
想い託してみては
寄存着这份思念
強さの本当の意味を
继续寻找着那
搜し続けてた
强大的真正意义
ありのままの痛みを
将各种痛苦
受け入れるその意味を
全部承受的意义
明日へ走り続ける君に知った
是奔向明天的你告诉了我
巡りゆく景色が今流れてく
那眼前的景色现已过去
手繰り寄せた世界の先
那紧牵着双手的世界的前方
降り注ぐシグナルを躰で感じて
身体已感觉到其中所倾注的信号
解き放つ今全てを
此刻解放所有一切
Just truth in my heart
いつだって迷わないよ
无论何时都不应迷茫
消せない想いがあるから
因为有着无法磨灭的思念
解き明かす真実から瞳を逸らさずに
直视那已经揭开的真相
I'll reach the next stage to realize all.
確かな絆信じて
请相信这份羁绊
固法先輩と黒妻が知り合い
Konori-sempai and Kurozuma knew each other?
うん　はっきりとしたことは言ってないんだけど
Yeah...
She never said anything about it though...
でも黒妻って言ったら
But, Kurozuma is...
<Big Spider>　　　　
大蜘蛛のボスですよね
the boss of Big Spider.
そうなんだけど
That's right...
その黒妻と　固法先輩がどうして
Why is Konori-sempai with...
そんなよってたかって女の子を襲うようなやつと
some bastard who tries to gang rape girls?
っあ　だからね その黒妻じゃないの
Umm well...
It wasn't the same Kurozuma...
It's not like that, but I mean...
そうじゃなくて　ええと
ちょっと黒子　アンタからも説明しなさいよ
Hey Kuroko, you try explaining it to them!
縁は異なもの味なもの
Encounters are strange and interesting.
Huh?
この件に関しては　私静観させていただきますわ
I'm just watching everything from the outside.
あ　もう気になる　もやもやする
It bothers me! I need to know!
こうなったら　固法先輩に直接聞いてみよう
Why don't we now go ask Konori-sempai directly?
それが
Well, you see...
先輩　ここ数日支部に出てきてないんです
Sempai hasn't been to the branch office for the past few days.
えっ　そうなの
Huh?
Really?
携帯も通じなくて
She won't answer her phone either.
例の能力者狩りだって まだ解決したわけじゃないのに
The Ability User Hunt incident hasn't been solved yet...
むしろ問題はそっちですわね
I guess that's the larger concern here.
気を揉んでいても始まりませんし
It's needless to worry about her.
この際足を運んだほうが
It's probably better to move it.
足を運ぶってどこに
Move it where?
はい
Yes.
どちら様
Who is it?
This is Konori Mii-sempai's place... right?
あっ　あの
こちら固法美偉先輩のお部屋です　よね
ああ　美偉の後輩
Oh you're Mii's Kouhai?
ごめんね　今あいつ出かけてるの
I'm sorry, she's out at the moment.
Oh, I see...
あっ　そうですか
あー　黒妻のことが聞きたかったのに
Geez... I wanted to ask her about Kurozuma.
仕方ないですよ
Well, that's too bad.
I understand.
あっ　分かりました
また出直します　失礼しました
We'll come back another time.
Excuse me.
Oh, wait a sec.
あー　ちょっと
本当にしょうがないわね
She really is horrible. She even worries her kouhai.
後輩にまで心配かけて
It's okay... really.
あっ　いいえ
それで　黒妻が戻って来たのね
So, it appears that Kurozuma is back.
まさか生きてたとはね
I would never have thought that he was still alive.
黒妻をご存知なんですか
You know Kurozuma?
あのう　先輩と黒妻はどういう
What kind of relationship does she have with Kurozuma?
ちょっ　ちょっと待って
Wait a second.
その前に　そっちの話を聞かせて
Before I get to that, let me hear what you know.
Huh?
そっか　道理でね
I see.
That explains it.
あの　それで 固法先輩はどうして黒妻のことを知ってたんですか
Umm.. and...
How did Konori-sempai know about Kurozuma?
Did she arrest Kurozuma in the past or something?
ひょっとして　先輩が前に黒妻を捕まえたことがあるとか
違う違う
No, it's not like that at all.
<Big Spider>　
美偉はね　昔大蜘蛛のメンバーだったの
Mii used to belong to Big Spider.
えー
What?!
ありえない　いくら何でもそれはない
That's impossible!
Out of all the possibilities, that's impossible!
<Judgement>
だって先輩は風紀委員ですよ
But sempai is in Judgement!
How could she had been involved in that?
それがどうして
ああ見えて　昔はやんちゃだったのよ
She might look like she does now, but she used to be pretty badass.
やんちゃって
Badass?
人様の過去をどうこう言うつもりはありませんけど
I don't really want to comment on other people's past but,
Konori-sempai is a Level 3 ability user.
<Level 3>
仮にも固法先輩は強能力の能力者
寄り道なら他にいくらでもあったでしょうに
She had countless other ways of enjoying herself.
<Skill Out>
なぜよりにもよって無能力者の集団である武装無能力者集団なんかと
Why, out of all choices she could have made, did she hang out with Skill-Outs — a group of ability-less people?
あなたにはない　能力の壁にぶっつかったこと
Have you ever experienced the feeling that you've reached the limit of your ability?
それがなかなか乗り越えられず
The feeling of struggling to get over an obstacle and getting depressed,
暗い気持ちを持て余したこと
Huh?
あの頃の美偉は
Mii, at that time, felt as if she had no place to go any more.
どこに行っても居場所がないって感じだった
That was when...
そんな時
She met people who shined brightly in a dark place.
輝いて見える人たちと出会った
Though they claimed to be Skill-Outs, they were just hanging out with other people they liked.
<Skill Out>
武装無能力集団と言っても
連中はただきのおけない仲間たちと一緒にバカやってただけ
Sure, I was worried at first.
そりゃ　最初私も心配したわ
I kept asking her if it was worth being with them,
わざわざ自分が能力者だってことを　隠してまでいるとこなのって
even if it meant keeping the fact that she was an ability user a secret from them.
でも
But...
"Big Spider is a place where I can express myself."
<Big Spider>　　　　　　　
大蜘蛛は　私が私でいられる場所
美偉は　そう言ってたわ
That's what Mii told me.
居場所　か
Her place, eh?
疎外感　自分探し
The feeling of being excluded...
Pursuing yourself...
That disease is like  the measles — you will
definitely catch it if you live in Academy City...
学園都市にいると必ず罹る麻疹みたいなものに
あの時の美偉も罹ってたのかも
Maybe Mii had it that time, also.
でも麻疹に罹るのは一度だけです
But someone can only catch the measles once.
Eh?
お姉様
Onee-sama?
Railing: Kuro | Mii
よう
Yo!
あっ　あの これは
Oh, I was just...
<Leve 2>
お前　異能力者なんだって
I hear you are a Level 2.
だったらこんなとこに
Then you shouldn't be—
居させて
Let me stay!
ここしか居場所がないんです
I have no where else to go.
I beg you!
お願いです
能力者ってのも面倒くせもんだな
Being an ability user is also difficult, I see.
まあ　いいけど
Well, it's fine, though.
けどよ　来年も再来年も　ここにいるつもりか
But you see...
Do you intend to stay here the next year and the year after?
まあ　決めるのはお前だ
Well, it's up to you to decide.
Railing: Kuro | Mii
先輩
Sempai...
分からない
I don't get it.
Onee-sama?
お姉様
<Skill Out>
固法先輩が武装無能力者集団だったのをショックだけど
Sure, it's shocking that Konori-sempai was with the Skill-Outs,
<Judgement>
だからって　なんで風紀委員休んでるの
but why does she need to take time off from Judgement?
何か関係あるわけ
Is there a connection here?
ですからそれは
Like I said that is...
昔は昔じゃない
The past is the past!
<Judgement>
今は先輩　風紀委員で頑張ってるわけじゃない
Sempai is working hard in Judgement now.
あたしたちにも優しくて
She's really nice to us. Sure she's a bit strict
sometimes, but she's always been dependable.
偶に厳しくて　頼りになって
そんな先輩が好きなのに
We like sempai for being like that, so why do we have to talk about her past now?
なのに　なんで今更
そんな簡単に割り切れないんじゃないかな
Maybe she can't forget about it that easily.
Your past makes you what you are today.
過去の自分があって　今の自分があるわけだし
それに　その過去が特別なものだとしたら
If that past happened to be something special,
なお更
then it's even more the case.
あっ　いや　違いますよ
Right?
No it's not like that.
I'm not objecting to you or anything...
別に　御坂さんに反対してるわけじゃ　ハハハハっ
Geez.
あぁ　もう やっぱり分かんないよ
I don't get this at all.
What now?
何だよ　集まり悪いな
しょうがねーだろう　あんなことがあった後じゃ
Attendance is horrible.
What can we do after that happened?
That's true.
まあな
なぁ 黒妻さんって　偽者だったのかな
Hey, was Kurozuma-san fake?
あっ　んなわけねーだろう
I refuse to believe it!
黒妻さんは黒妻さんだよ
Kurozuma-san is Kurozuma-san.
でもよ　あの人　蛇谷って呼ばれてびびってなかったか
But remember,
he freaked out when he was called Hebitani.
お前も見たか
You saw that, too?
やっぱ　びびってたよな
He was really freaked out.
Who'd you say was freaked out?
誰が　びびってたって
く　黒妻さん
K-Kurozuma-san!
If you got time to doubt me, then you've got time to find and mess up that fucking fake!
この俺を疑ってる暇があったら
今すぐあの偽者やろうを見つけ出して打ち殺せ
学園都市に黒妻綿流は二人もいらねーんだ
We don't need two Kurozuma Watarus in Academy City!
はい
Y-Yes!
Now hurry up!
ほら　急げー
行くぞ
Go!
ほら　速く行けーよ
We're going!
待てって
Wait up!
もしもし　あぁ　俺だ
Hello?
Yeah, it's me.
<CapacityDown>
あっ　　キャパシティダウン
Huh?
The Capacity Down?
ちゃんと使ってるぜ
We're making good use of it.
うせーな　こっちもごたごたしてんだよ
Shut the fuck up!
We have some important damn business here, too!
今能力者狩りどころじゃね
There's stuff more important than Ability User Hunting!
何だと
What the fuck?
御坂さん　あれからずっとあんななんですか
Has Misaka-san been like that ever since?
Yes.
ええ　まあ
Well...
Huh?
<Antilskill>
あれ　警備員からメールだ
There's mail from Anti-Skill.
Huh?
Uhh...
うん　ええと
<Antiskill><Skill Out>
警備員本部は武装無能力者集団の能力者狩りに対抗し
To counter the Skill-Outs, the Anti-skill headquarters will conduct a coordinated crack down...
明朝１０時より第十学区エリアＧ　通称ストレンジの一斉摘発を行う
on the 10th Academy District Area G,
A.K.A. Strange tomorrow morning at 10.
TL Note: This is the same notice that Uiharu was reading.
Mii, you forgot something.
美偉
忘れ物
So you came here, after all.
やっぱりここだったんですね
学
园
都
市
A Certain Scientific Railgun
Academy
City
御坂さん
Misaka-san...
こんなとこで何してるんですか
Why are you here?
ひょっとして　明日の一斉摘発のことを　黒妻に知らせに来たんですか
You're not here to tip off Kurozuma about the crackdown tomorrow, are you?
ここは　固法先輩がいる所じゃないと思います
I don't think this is the right place for you to be.
そうね　ここは私の居場所じゃない
That's right.
This isn't the right place for me.
But, you see...
でもね　それを私に教えてくれたのは　黒妻なの
It was Kurozuma who taught me that.
先輩　行かないでください
Sempai, please don't go!
Text: No Subject    I've taken that idiot Hebitani as hostage. Come alone if you want him back.
つーでも　蛇谷を見捨てるわけにゃいかねーだろう
You say that, but I can't just leave Hebitani.
It's just a trap anyway!
そんなの　罠に決まってるじゃないですか
Oh yeah, I told you before but,
そう言や　この間の話だけど
やっぱり　ここは　お前の名前を刻む場所じゃないと　俺は思うぜ
this place is not the place for you to engrave your name.
先輩
Sempai...
私が駆けつけた時には
When I rushed to the scene...
そして 今の私がいる
And... here I am now.
でも　だからって
But... Even so...
<Judgement>
先輩は風紀委員じゃないですか
You're in Judgement, now!
犯罪者を逃がすとかおかしいじゃないですか
It's wrong to let criminals escape!
それで
That's—
Yeah.
ああ　間違ってるよな
It's wrong, right?
先輩
Sempai?
あれから二年か
Two years have passed since then, hmm?
あの後　目を覚ましたら病院でさ
After all that, I woke up in the hospital.
そのまま施設によくられて
I was sent straight to the institution,
出て来れってのが　ほんの半年前
and they just released me 6 months ago.
先輩　私
Sempai, I...
この景色も　もう二度と見ることはないと思ってたんだけどな
I never thought I would see this scenery ever again.
お前にも　会わないほうがいいと思ってた
I thought I would never meet you again, either.
会えば　また
Since, if we meet, we will once again...
また　一人で乗り込むつもりですか　あの時みたいに
Again? Are you going alone? Just like that time...
<Big Spider>
大蜘蛛を作ったのは俺だ
I'm the one who established Big Spider.
だから潰すのも俺
So I'm the one who has to crush it.
<Antiskill>
警備員じゃない
Not the Anti-Skills.
行かないで
Don't go!
あなたはいつだってそう
You're always like that!
自分勝手に人を思い遣って
Always thinking about others...
自分勝手に行動して
and acting selfishly.
あなたがそんなだから 私は
Because you're like that, I'm...!
お前だってそうじゃねーか
Aren't you like that, too?
だからここに来てるんだろう
That's why you're here, right?
さぁ　もういいから　帰れ
So...
Just go home, now.
ほら　あの子もさっきから困ってるじゃねーか
She looks puzzled, too.
See ya.
じゃな
今いる所を大切にしろよ
Take care of the people and places where you are now.
私も行きます
I'm going, too.
もう　あんな思いはしたくないんです
I don't want to experience something like that ever again.
いい加減にしろよ美偉
Enough, Mii.
昔と今じゃ違うだろう
Things have changed...
俺とお前じゃ
between you and me.
今とか昔とか　関係ありません
It has nothing to do with the past or right now!
居場所が変わっても　私の気持ちは変わりません
Even if my place changes, my feelings won't!
ねぇ　黒子
Hey Kuroko,
時間が経っても　立場が変わっても
even if times and positions change,
それでも変わらない思いってあるのかな
are there still emotions that don't ever change?
むしろ　誰かが誰かを思うと言うのは　そういうことなのかも
Isn't that what loving someone is all about?
Huh?
そして　そんな思いの積み重ねが
And the thing that makes someone shine
right now is the build-up of those emotions.
その人の今を輝かせている
積み重ね
Build-up...
口幅ったいですけど
I might sound presumptuous, but...
お姉様と私にだって
Even though it's been short, there are things the two of us have built up in the time we've spent together.
短いながらも　積み重ねて来たものが
そっか
I see.
そしてそれは　これからも積み重なって行くんだね
And we will still continue to build them up from now on.
あのさ　黒子
You know Kuroko,
ちょっと頼みがあるんだけど
Will you do me a favor?
これより第十学区エリアＧ
From here on, we will conduct a coordinated crack down on Academy District Area G, A.K.A. Strange.
通称ストレンジの一斉摘発を行う
乗車
Man your vehicles!
あなたたち
You two...
どうして
Why?
ちょっ　ちょっと　何なの　これ
Oh hey!
What is this?
うん　やっぱりこうでなくちゃ
This is how you should be.
これ　私の　どうやって
This is my...
How did you?
固法先輩
Konori-sempai...
カッコいいですよ
You look cool.
朝っぱらから忙しそうだな
Looks like people are working hard early in the morning.
終わらせに来たぜ
I've come to put an end to it.
こいつ　この前の
He's...
The guy from last time!
てめー
Damn you!
分かってるだろうけど
I guess you know but,
俺は強えーぞ
I'm strong.
ああ　確かにアンタは強エ
Yeah.
You're really strong.
だがな　そんななら能力者と一緒だ
But people say the same thing about ability users!
数と武器には敵い来ねーんだ
You're no match against our numbers and our weapons!
待ちなさい
Wait a minute!
美偉
Mii...
カッコいいじゃねーか
You look cool.
固法さん
Konori-san?
蛇谷君
Hebitani-kun,
あなた　随分下種な男に成り下がったわね
you really have become quite the lowlife.
数にものを言わせて
You're using sheer numbers as
power and even wielding weapons.
その上　武器
うるせー
Shut up!
<Judgement>
俺たちを裏切って風紀委員なんかになって行く何がわかる
What would you understand, after betraying us and becoming Judgement?!
Now, show them our power!
ほら　こいつらに俺たちの力を見せてやれ
今度は　直接体内にお見舞いしましょうか
Shall I drive them straight into your body next time?
っだ　だが　俺たちにはあれが
But we have that—
あれって
By that, you mean...
これのこと
This?
まさか　同じ罠に二度引っ掛かるなんて思ってないわよね
You don't think we would fall for the same trick twice, do you?
やれ　やっちまえ
Get them! Get them now!
だ　だけど
B-But...
<Railgun>
あいつ　常盤台の超電磁砲ですよ
She's the Railgun from Tokiwadai!
<Railgun>
超電磁砲
Railgun?!
We're no match!
What do we do?!
やるんだよ
I told you to get them!
やらなきゃ俺がお前らをやっちまうぞ
Get going or I'll kill you guys!
あなたたちは手を出さないで
You two stay out of this.
Let your sempai show off sometimes, okay?
偶には先輩を立てなさい
Eh?
こら　行け
Now go!
Hey, man.
おいおい
You need to get more serious.
もうちょっと気合入れてかかって来ねーと
張り合いがねーぞこら
This is too easy!
これは没収ね
I'll be taking this away.
それと　そのスタンガンもね
And this Stun-gun too.
なんで
How...?
それがお前の能力か
So that's your ability.
すげーじゃねーか
That's good.
でしょう
Isn't it?
俺も負けてなんねーな
Now I gotta show off too!
さて　どうするよ
So then.
What will you do now?
これで勝ったつもりかよ
You think you've won?!
これを　見ろー
Watch this!
Dynamite!
ダイナマイト
A suicide bombing?!
わっ　いつの時代の方ですの
これ以上近づいてみろ
If you come any closer,
everybody will get blown up!
みんなドッガーンだ
Eh?
どうだ
So?
どうした　びびったか
What do you do now?
Freaked out now?
Man, it's so much trouble.
ああ　面倒くせー
くっ　来るな
D-Don't come!
ドッガーンだぞ
You'll blow up!
蛇谷
Hebitani, we had a lot of fun back then.
昔が楽しかったよな
来るな　来るなって
Don't come!
I told you not to come!
みんなでするんって　バカやって
We would just hang out together and do stupid stuff...
それがどうしちまった
What's gotten into you, now?
く　来る　な
Don't come...
どうしちまったよ　蛇谷
What's gotten into you, Hebitani...
しょっ　しょうがなかった　しょうがなかったんだよ
I-I had no choice.
I really had no choice...
俺たちの居場所はここしかねー
We had no other place to be.
<Big Spider>
大蜘蛛をまとめるには
I had to be Kurozuma to lead Big Spider.
俺が黒妻じゃなきゃだめだったんだ
だから　今更てめーなんかいらねーんだ
That's why...
you're not needed any more!
蛇谷　居場所ってのは
Hebitani,
your "place to be" means the place that you can be yourself.
自分が自分で居られる所を言うんだよ
Well, it's all finished.
あー　終わった　終わった
ほら
Now,
美偉
Mii.
黒妻綿流　あなたを暴行傷害の容疑で拘束します
Kurozuma Wataru.
You are under arrest on the charge of assault and battery.
似合ってるぜ
You look great.
でもよ
But, well.
その革ジャン　さすがに胸　きつくねーか
Isn't that leather jacket a bit tight on your chest?
そりゃ　毎日あれ飲んでましたから
Of course.
狙い定めた指先が指す
Since I've been drinking that every day.
やっぱり牛乳は　ムサシの牛乳
If we're having milk,
運命は絶望 それとも希望
It's gotta be Musashino Milk!
ハハハハっ
やっぱり胸のことをお話になって
They're talking about chest sizes again.
ゆらぎの中で受信してゆく
不思議と違和らしくない
Strangely, somehow it doesn't sound perverted.
先輩
Sempai...
悲しみにも負けない
勇気だけをください
Thank you.
ありがとう
大切なもの　守るため
「強さ」があると信じてる
Saving our future 一緒に
明日へのドア明けいた空へ飛び立とう
とある世界の果てで
駆け抜けてくReal Force
光を放って
ああ　確かに　ここは風が気持ちいいねー
The wind really does feel nice here.
お姉様ったら　わざわざそのためにここまで
Onee-sama, you came all the way for this?
あら　今時相合傘なんて
Huh?
Aiaigasa are so out of fashion, now.
Mii loves Kuro...
ミイ　クロ
猫ですの
Are they cats or something?
It means that, even in a place like this, the
feeling of one loving each other still remains.
こんな所でもさ
誰かが誰かを思う気持ちはあるってことよ
学園都市　か
Academy City, eh?
Next Episode
先輩忘れません
Sempai, I'll never forget...
暑假琐事
Tsuzuri
During
Summer
Vacation
all "those" games you taught me.
あなたに教えてもらったあんなことやこんなこと
天にも登る女の喜び
The happiness of being a woman... it allows you to rise up the skies.
って　何　このやらしいコメント
Hey, what's with these perverted lines?!
罰ゲームですの
It's your punishment for losing.